ANATOLY YAKOVENKO

aeyakovenko@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Software developer with over 10 years of experience in embedded operating systems, developing <u>patents</u>, leading projects and contributing to large groups including <u>Linux Kernel</u>, with a focus on performance and optimization for Qualcomm ARM and DSP processors.

SKILLS

Hardware and Systems

• Embedded Operating Systems, Linux Kernel, Android, Qualcomm MSMs, System MMUs, ARM, Hexagon DSP

Languages and Tools

• C, C++, Haskell, Lua, Make, Bash, Python, Ruby, Git, Perforce, GDB, Trace32

WORK EXPERIENCE

Qualcomm, San Diego CA

Senior Staff Engineer, 2012 to Present Staff Engineer, 2008 - 2012 Senior Engineer, 2006 - 2009 Engineer, 2003 - 2006

- Heterogenous Multicore Compute
 Lead developer of a brand new technology featured in Hexagon SDK for off-loading computations between ARM and DSP co-processors on Qualcomm's mobile chips.
 Achieved a 10x reduction in co-processor communication latency. Developed several patents, and commercialized on Android, Windows and Qnx. Enabled cutting edge Computer Vision, Augmented Reality, 3d camera technologies utilizing Qualcomm's DSP on numerous devices.
- Mobile Operating Systems
 Lead developer of Inter-Process Communication for BREW, Qualcomm's mobile
 operating systems a capability based object oriented embedded operating system,
 shipped on thousands of devices, millions of units, with billion of 3rd party application
 downloads. Developed developer frameworks, tools, and custom Interface Description
 Language compiler. Lead interface reviews with a focus on binary backwards
 compatibility, security, and performance.
- QChat Push To Talk
 Developed network components using SIP/HTTP/RTP and proprietary standards for
 QChat push to talk service. Designed high performance logging tools to handle tens of
 thousands of transactions per second from many networked components with a real time monitoring system.

Alescere LLC, Lisle IL

Co-Founder, 2001 to 2003

• Founding member of <u>Alescere</u>, a VOIP startup Lead development of SIP and <u>RTP</u> protocol stacks, and server components for a VoIP system for small businesses.

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Research Assistant, 2003

- Developed a web server that supports QoS for HTTP requests
- Designed a probabilistic scheduler for the Linux kernel
- Implemented a roaming protocol for 802.11a/b networks for NetBSD

Personal Research

 Neural Networks, Genetic Algorithms, Markov Models, and Bayesian Inference Algorithms

References

- Brian Kelley, Senior Director of Technology, bkelley@quicinc.com
- Rob Walker, Senior Director of Engineering, rwalker@quicinc.com
- Ramesh Chandrasekhar, Director of Engineering, rameshc@qti.qualcomm.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2003